Heroes are ordinary men who do extraordinary things in extraordinary times.
U-571 is a war, action, adventure film directed by Jonathan Mostow.
In the midst of World War II, the battle under the sea rages and the Nazis have
the upper hand as the Allies are unable to crack their war codes.
However, after a wrecked U-boat sends out an SOS signal, the Allies realise
this is their chance to seize the 'enigma coding machine'.
Lt. Andrew Tyler, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Lt. Cmdr. Mike Dahlgren, played by Bill Paxton.
CPO Henry Klough, played by Harvey Keitel.
Lt. Pete Emmett, played by Jon Bon Jovi.
Maj. Matthew Coonen, played by David Keith.
Capt. Lt. Gunther Wassner, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
U-571 is a 2000 submarine film directed by Jonathan Mostow from a
screenplay he co-wrote with Sam Montgomery and David Ayer.
The film stars Matthew McConaughey, Bill Paxton, Harvey Keitel,
Jon Bon Jovi, Jake Weber and Matthew Settle.
The film follows a World War II German U-boat boarded by American
submariners to capture her Enigma cipher machine.
Although the film was financially successful and received generally positive reviews from critics, winning the Academy
Award for Best Sound Editing, the fictitious plot was subject to substantial controversy and criticism.
The film explores themes of mission, submarine, world
war ii, north atlantic, enigma machine.